A Finding Aid to the Maryette Charlton papers, circa 1890-2013, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Major Film Projects, 1904-2007; Series 8; Archival Resource Key; 18.8 Linear feet Boxes 43-61, 81-82, FC 90-91, OV 87; 0.34 Gigabytes ER01
  - Loren MacIver, 1938-1998; 8.4; Archival Resource Key
    - Festival of Women's Films, Archival Resource Key (Box 58)
      - "I Salute You, Kristina Nordstrom" Article and Drafts, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 22)
    - Disbound "Film Research" Scrapbook, 1938-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 58, Folder 23)
    - Disbound "Film Research" Scrapbook, 1938-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - Disbound "Film History" Scrapbook, 1956-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 59, Folder 2-3)
    - Film-Maker's Cooperative Catalogue No. 5, 1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 59, Folder 4)
    - Film-Maker's Cooperative Catalogue No. 6, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 59, Folder 5)
    - Loren MacIver Obituary, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 59, Folder 6)
    - Radim Film Catalogs, 1963-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 59, Folder 7-8)
    - Loren MacIver Exhibition Catalogs, 1949-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 59, Folder 9-10)
    - Loren MacIver Signed Exhibition Catalogs, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 59, Folder 11)
    - Group Exhibition Catalogs, 1946-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 59, Folder 12-15)
    - Articles and News Clippings, 1948-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 59, Folder 16)
    - Printed Material, 1962-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 59, Folder 17)
    - Printed Material, 1974-1992; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 1-2)
    - Loren MacIver Photograph Album, 1962-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Loren MacIver Contact Sheets, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Loren MacIver images on film, 1956-1976; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel film strips found in the same can were spliced together 16mm (Item FC 92)
    - Loren MacIver images on film-excerpts, 1956-1973; Archival Resource Key; 1 Film reel film strips found in the same can were spliced together 16mm (Item FC 93)
    - Loren MacIver Film Rolls, circa 1951; Archival Resource Key; 35mm photographic transparencies in canisters (Box 60, Folder 6-7)
    - "Louise Crane" and "Crane House, Wisteria", circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key; 2 Film reels Trims 16 mm (Box 60, Folder 8)
    - Oversized Printing Plates from Box 56, Folder 17, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 82)
    - Oversized "Title Shooting" Cards from Box 58, Folder 15, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 82)
    - Oversized Contact Sheets from Box 60, Folder 4, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 82)
  - Jeanne Reynal, 1961-1983; 8.5; Archival Resource Key
    This subseries consists of material on Maryette Charlton's film about sculptor and mosaicist Jeanne Reynal. Included are research materials, editing notes, contracts, screening notes, shooting cards, exhibition catalogs, and photographs.
    - Film Bills and Expenses, 1962-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 9)
    - Film Contract and Correspondence, 1961-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 10)
    - Film Editing Notes, 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 11)
    - Film Research Material, 1976-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 12)
    - Film Screening Notes, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 13)
    - Film Shooting Cards, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 14)
    - Film Shooting On-Site in Florida, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - Film Sound Studies by Ann McMillan, 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 16)
    - The Mosaics of Jeanne Reynal, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 17)
    - Exhibition Catalogs, 1962-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 18)
    - Photographs Album of Artwork, 1961-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 60, Folder 19)
      Photographs of mosaics and a few photographs of Jeanne Reynal working.
    - "NYU" Film Stills and Negatives, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - "Florida Monograph" Contact Sheets and Negatives, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 2)
- Exhibition Files, 1950-2000; Series 9; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Boxes 61-62
  Files on Maryette Charlton's group and solo exhibitions includes catalogs, announcements, clippings, printed material, mailing lists, art inventory, sales lists, limited correspondence, and other material.
  This series is arranged chronologically. Before processing, the folders in this series were scattered throughout the collection. The original folder titles were retained. Folders with exhibition titles, venues, or locations are arranged chronologically at the beginning on the series. Exhibitions without titles or locations are grouped together in chronological folders toward the end of the series.
  - Chicago Maryette Charlton Exhibitions, 1950-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 3-5)
  - Beirut Maryette Charlton Exhibitions, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 6-9)
  - Hull House - Charlton-Gruse Exhibition (1951), Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - New Trier High School Gallery - Maryette Charlton Exhibition (1951), Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - National Arts Club - Annual Art Show (1960), Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Modernage Gallery - Maryette Charlton Photographs Exhibition (1974), Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 13-15)
  - Limbo Theater - "Handmade Postcards by Performers" (1986), 1985-1986; Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Baron/Boisante - Group Art Show (1990), Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Gallerie Valerie - "Maryette Charlton: Early Works" (2000), Archival Resource Key (Box 61)
    - Valerie Ahms Correspondence, 1998-2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 18)
    - Exhibition Announcement, 1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 19)
    - Expenses and Sales, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 20)
    - Framing, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 21)
    - Guest Book, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - Gallerie Valerie - "Maryette Charlton: Early Works" (2000), Archival Resource Key (Box 62)
    - Hanging and Pricing, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 62, Folder 1)
    - Mailing Lists, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 62, Folder 2)
    - Resume and Art Inventory, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Chronological Maryette Charlton Exhibitions, 1952-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 62, Folder 4-9)
- Printed Material, 1924-2000; Series 10; Archival Resource Key; 3.2 Linear feet Boxes 62-65, 82, OV 87
  Printed material includes exhibition catalogs, books, posters, magazines, and clippings. There are several books on color theory dating from Maryette Charlton's job as a color analyst for the Container Corporation of America. Of particular note is a copy of Twenty Years at Hull House signed by Jane Addams. There is a lot of printed material on Frederick Kiesler.
  The folders in this series are grouped together by document type, then arranged chronologically within each grouping. More printed material can be found in the addition to the Maryette Charlton papers.
  - Color Theory Books, 1935-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 62, Folder 10-12)
  - Color Theory Books, 1942-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 1-4)
  - Al-Kulliyah, Vol. 28, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 5)
  - The Artist's World in Pictures, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Artistic Collaboration in the Twentieth Century, 1984; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 7)
  - escape_space, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 8)
  - Frederick Kiesler, Environmental Artist, 1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 9)
  - The Gentle Giraffe, 1945; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 10)
  - Junior Arts and Activities, 1952-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 11-12)
  - Legionnaire, 10th Anniversary Issue, 1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 13)
  - Metropolis Magazine, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 14)
    Oversized magazine housed in Box 82.
  - Philip Davis, A Celebration, 1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 15)
  - Ragdale: A History and Guide, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 63, Folder 16)
  - Twenty Years at Hull House, 1924; Archival Resource Key (Box 64, Folder 1)
    Book is signed by Jane Addams.
  - Frederick Kiesler Exhibition Announcements, 1966-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 64, Folder 2-3)
  - Frederick Kiesler Exhibition Catalogs, 1964-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 64, Folder 4-9)
  - Frederick Kiesler Clippings, 1954-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 64, Folder 10-12)
  - Frederick Kiesler Exhibition Press Releases, 1966-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 64, Folder 13)
  - Frederick Kiesler Theater and Set Design Reviews, 1929-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 64, Folder 14)
  - Frederick Kiesler Printed Material, 1972-1997; Archival Resource Key (Box 64, Folder 15-17)
  - 31st Venice Biennale Poster, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 64, Folder 18)
    Oversized poster housed in OV 87.
  - Le Royal Saint Germain Poster, circa 1960-circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 64, Folder 19)
  - Clippings about Maryette Charlton, 1951-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 64, Folder 20)
  - Printed Material with Photographs by Maryette Charlton, 1954-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 64, Folder 21-22)
  - Beirut Printed Material, 1952-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 1-2)
  - Assorted Exhibition Catalogs, 1966-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 3-5)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Material, 1964-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - Oversized Metropolis Magazine from Box 63, Folder 14, 1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 82)
  - Oversized Venice Biennale Poster from Box 64, Folder 18, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 87)
  - Oversized Le Royal Saint Germain Poster from Box 64, Folder 19, circa 1960-circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 87)
- Scrapbooks, 1939-2010; Series 11; Archival Resource Key; 0.8 Linear feet Box 65, 82-83
  Scrapbooks document Maryette Charlton's personal life from high school, college, and summer camp, exhibitions, and miscellaneous subjects.
  - High School Scrapbook, 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 7)
    Oversized scrapbook housed in Box 82.
  - Camp Good Health Disbound Scrapbook, 1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 8)
  - Monticello College Scrapbooks, 1942-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 9)
    Oversized scrapbooks housed in Box 83.
  - Exhibitions Disbound Scrapbook, 1972-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 10)
  - Miscellaneous Disbound Scrapbook, 1972-2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 11-12)
  - Oversized High School Scrapbook from Box 65, Folder 7, 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 82)
  - Oversized Monticello College Scrapbooks from Box 65, Folder 9, 1942-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 83)
- Artwork, 1950-1998; Series 12; Archival Resource Key; 0.9 Linear feet Boxes 65-66, 84
  Most of the sketches and drawings in this series are by Maryette Charlton and Lillian Kiesler with a few drawings by Elizabeth Gruse Dixon and Margo Hoff. There is also a batch of mail art by various artists.
  The materials in this series are grouped together by document type. Drawings are arranged alphabetically by artist. The mail art is from several disbound binders and do not have a clear arrangement within the folders.
  - Drawings by Maryette Charlton, circa 1950-circa 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 13-15)
  - "Eternity" Framed Drawing by Maryette Charlton, circa 1960-circa 1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 16)
  - Drawings by Elizabeth Gruse Dixon, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 17)
  - Drawing by Margo Hoff, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 18)
  - Drawings by Lillian Kiesler, 1983-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 19)
    Oversized drawings housed in Box 84.
  - Mail Art by Various Artists, 1980-1981; Archival Resource Key (Box 65, Folder 20-23)
  - Mail Art by Various Artists, 1980-1998; Archival Resource Key (Box 66, Folder 1-5)
  - Oversized Drawings by Lillian Kiesler from Box 65, Folder 19, 1983-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 84)
- Sketchbooks, 1949-1996; Series 13; Archival Resource Key; 0.5 Linear feet Box 66
  This series consists of 22 sketchbooks that span most of Maryette Charlton's professional life and include pencil, ink, and crayon drawings and sketches. There are occasional annotations. Most of the sketchbooks are untitled.
  The sketchbooks are arranged chronologically. The American University of Beirut sketchbooks are grouped together because Charlton wrote on the covers that they are from the same time period and location.
  - Sketchbook, 1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 66, Folder 6)
  - Sketchbook, 1950; Archival Resource Key (Box 66, Folder 7)
  - Sketchbooks, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 66, Folder 8)
    Includes 2 sketchbooks.
  - Sketchbook, 1951-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 66, Folder 9)
  - American University of Beirut Sketchbooks, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 66, Folder 10-13)
    Includes 8 sketchbooks.
  - Sketchbook, 1965-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 66, Folder 14)
  - Sketchbooks, 1974-1975; Archival Resource Key (Box 66, Folder 15)
    Includes 3 small sketchbooks.
  - Sketchbooks, 1975-1996; Archival Resource Key (Box 66, Folder 16)
    Includes 2 small sketchbooks.
  - Sketchbook, 1976-1978; Archival Resource Key (Box 66, Folder 17)
  - Sketchbooks, 1981-1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 66, Folder 18)
- Photographic Materials, circa 1890-circa 2010; Series 14; Archival Resource Key; 7.8 Linear feet Boxes 67-74, 84-86
  This series includes photographs, slides, negatives, and albums. There are portraits and photographs of Maryette Charlton and her photographs and snapshots of travels abroad, family, friends, and artists. Additional photographs are found in many other series as well. The addition to the Maryette Charlton papers also includes a small number of photographs.
  This series is arranged as 4 subseries.
  14.1: Photographs of Maryette Charlton, 1927-circa 2010
  14.2: Photographs by Subject, circa 1890-2000
  14.3: Personal Photographs by Maryette Charlton, 1945-1989
  14.4: Snapshots of and by Maryette Charlton, 1942-1984
  - Photographs of Maryette Charlton, 1927-circa 2010; 14.1; Archival Resource Key
    - Maryette Charlton Portraits by Roland Sidawy, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Maryette Charlton Editing Film in Studio, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Maryette Charlton While Filmmaking, 1962-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 3-4)
    - Maryette Charlton at Joy Farm by Marion Morehouse, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Maryette Charlton at Schooley's Mountain, 1972-1985; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Chronological Photographs of Maryette Charlton, circa 1927-circa 2010; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 7-15)
  - Photographs by Subject, circa 1890-2000; 14.2; Archival Resource Key
    - Antioch College, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 16)
    - Artist Slides, Archival Resource Key (Box 67)
      - Abercrombie-De Diego, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 17)
      - Chapin-Kahn, 1950-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 18)
      - Lanyon-Weber, 1951-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 19)
    - Beirut, Lebanon, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 20)
    - Beirut, Lebanon, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Box 21)
    - Beirut, Lebanon, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 67, Folder 22)
    - Beirut, Lebanon Disbound Album, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 1-2)
    - Buehr, George Slides, Archival Resource Key (Box 68)
      - Chicago and Mexico Paintings, 1950-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 3)
      - Colorado Painting, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 4)
      - Middle East and Colorado, 1950-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 5)
    - Calder, Alexander and Louisa, circa 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 6)
    - "Calders and Seyrigs in Beirut", 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Calder Artwork Slides, 1972-1974; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Cavallo, Diana, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 9)
    - Chicago, 1943-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 10)
    - Chicago Album, 1943-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 11)
      Oversized album housed in Box 84.
    - Constitution Yacht Sailing, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 12)
      Includes photographs with Leone and Owen Elliott as well as Loren MacIver.
    - D'Harnoncourt, Rene, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 13)
    - Egypt - Children's Tapestries in Giza, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 14)
    - Egypt - Hassan Fathy and New Gourna, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 15)
    - Family Album, circa 1890-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 16)
    - Family Album, 1939-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 17)
    - Family Portraits, 1966-1999; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 18)
    - Family Reunions and Gatherings, 1959-1982; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 19)
    - Family Vacations and Weddings, 1937-1983; Archival Resource Key (Box 68, Folder 20)
    - Family Miscellaneous, 1936-1979; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 1)
    - Festival of Women's Films, 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 2)
    - Finnegan's Wake Contact Prints, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 3)
    - Franklin, Ruth Stephan - Stone Legend, 1965-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 4-5)
    - Franklin, Ruth Stephan - 13M Stills, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 6)
    - Friends and Family Album, 1970-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 7)
    - Gallerie Valerie Maryette Charlton Exhibition Opening, 2000; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 8-11)
    - Greek Islands, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 12)
    - Hoff, Margo Slides, Archival Resource Key (Box 69)
      - Chicago, 1950-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 13)
        Box label indicates slides are of "Paintings, Galleries, Schools, Portraits"
      - Colorado Paintings, 1950-1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 14)
      - Mexico and New Mexico, 1950-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 15)
      - Middle East Paintings, 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 16)
    - Homologies of Pentadactyl Limbs, circa 1950-circa 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 17)
    - Italy, 1952; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 18)
    - Japan, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 69, Folder 19)
    - Jerash, Jordan, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 1)
    - Joy Farm, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 2)
    - Junior Arts and Activities Photographs for Article, 1952-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 3)
    - Kiesler, Frederick - "Samothrace" Sculpture, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 4)
    - Kiesler, Lillian, Archival Resource Key (Box 70)
      - Photographs with Friends, 1979-1994; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 5)
      - Son's Wedding, 1993; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 6)
      - Slides, 1966-1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 7)
        Slides of Lillian Kiesler at various locations and events and some photos of houses, gardens, and artwork.
    - Kiesler Springs Cemetary Plot, 1973; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 8)
    - Lebanon, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 9)
    - Lebanon Disbound Album, 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 10)
      Includes photographs of Alexander Calder.
    - Lebanon - Feast at Antar Bekaa, circa 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 11)
    - Life Magazine Photography Contest Submissions, 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 70, Folder 12-17)
    - MacIver, Loren, Archival Resource Key (Box 71)
      - Central Park with Kirk Winslow, 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 1)
      - Jones Beach and Fishers Island, 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 2)
      - Paris and Venice with Lloyd Frankenberg, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 3)
      - Paris Studio, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 4)
      - Film Program Layout, circa 1965-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 5)
      - Charcoal Drawing, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 6)
      - Slides of Artwork, circa 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 7)
      - Slides of Paris and Venice with Lloyd Frankenberg, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 8)
    - Manchester, Iowa Album, circa 1935; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 9)
    - Manchester, Iowa Album, 1935-1939; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 10)
    - Manchester, Iowa, 1939-1942; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 11)
    - "Matisse Party, St. Patrick's Day", 1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 12)
    - Monticello College, 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 13)
    - Monticello College Album, 1942-1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 14)
    - Monticello College Album, 1942-1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 15)
    - Morehouse, Marion, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 16)
    - Paintings and Drawings by Maryette Charlton, 1953-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 17)
    - Portraits Album, circa 1950-circa 1980; Archival Resource Key (Box 71, Folder 18)
      Photographs of various individuals, photographer might be Hall Winslow.
    - Portraits of Friends and Family by Maryette Charlton, 1962-1976; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 1)
    - Portraits of Unidentified Individuals, circa 1940-circa 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 2)
    - Pratt Institute, 1945-1947; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 3)
    - Ray School of Photography, 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 4)
      Oversized photographs are housed in Box 85.
    - Ryerson Street in Brooklyn, New York, circa 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 5)
    - Schooley's Mountain, 1968-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 6)
    - Schooley's Mountain Studio, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 7)
    - Seyrig, Henri - Birthday, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 8)
    - Seyrig, Henri - New York City Lecture, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 9)
    - Seyrigs in Beirut, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 10)
    - Seyrigs in Paris, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 11)
    - Seyrigs at Princeton, 1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 12)
    - Seyrigs at Schooley's Mountain, 1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 13)
    - Spain, circa 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 14)
    - Syria Disbound Album, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 15)
    - Syria, circa 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 16)
    - Travel Disbound Album of Spain, Greece, and Jordan, circa 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 17)
    - Travel to Various Locations, 1947-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 18)
    - University of Colorado Summer School, 1946; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 19)
    - Von Brockdorff, Louise "FiFi" Medbery, 1966-1971; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 20)
    - Wedding Photographs, 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 21)
    - Wedding and Baby Album, 1953-1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 22)
    - Winslow, Hall, Archival Resource Key (Box 72)
      - Family Album, circa 1969-1991; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 23)
        Oversized album housed in Box 85.
      - Lebanon Album, circa 1952-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 72, Folder 24)